<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on just some developer thoughts</title>
    <link>http://blog.noxy.site/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on just some developer thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 09:03:20 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.noxy.site/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Best Kubernetes Development Workflow</title>
      <link>http://blog.noxy.site/posts/best-kubernetes-development-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 09:03:20 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.noxy.site/posts/best-kubernetes-development-workflow/</guid>
      <description>At the start I want to point out that all opinions in this piece are just that - opinions. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried multiple workflows and all I want to do in this article is sharing what I&amp;rsquo;ve landed at and what difficulties I&amp;rsquo;ve had using other methods of developing in kubernetes. My main motivation for writing it is sparing someone difficutlies related with setting up dev environment. There are many solutions out there claiming that make working with k8s easier, but as usually with greater ease of development comes another layer of abstraction that sometimes might actually make things worse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I&#39;ve reduced CI rust tests duration 4x with caching and Nix!</title>
      <link>http://blog.noxy.site/posts/how-i-reduced-ci-rust-tests-duration-35-times-with-caching-and-nix/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 09:03:20 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.noxy.site/posts/how-i-reduced-ci-rust-tests-duration-35-times-with-caching-and-nix/</guid>
      <description>One of my project consists of backend (rust) split into many services and frontend made with Svelte. Sooner rather than later I found out that rust builds that we&amp;rsquo;re rather quick locally took ages in CI, resulting in poor CI feedback experience and test times exceeding 15minutes. This post was made to help people struggling with simmilar issues.
Project Structure The way I structure my projects will influence some of the futhurer solutions, so I thought it&amp;rsquo;s worthwhile sharing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Nix to make reproducible dev environments</title>
      <link>http://blog.noxy.site/posts/using-nix-for-dev-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 09:03:20 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.noxy.site/posts/using-nix-for-dev-environment/</guid>
      <description>Hello everone. Perhaps just like me you see value in making easily reproducible dev environments. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be great if you could have projects with different versions of dependencies that anyone could just jump right into, type command or two and have everything necesarry for contributing?
Well, I think it&amp;rsquo;s something that everone should take into consideration. Reproducible dev environments have one more pro - there&amp;rsquo;re self-documenting state of your project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
